Sameer Ahmad

sameer_9291@hotmail.com +44-7375116969

8 years of experience developing reliable web applications and backend system. I am eager to writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. I have worked on wide variety of technologies, such as Typescript, Javascript, C#, NodeJS, NestJS, Golang, ReactJS. I enjoy developing app whether it's microservices, a single-page app, API, Frontend or testing.

Linkedin sameer-ahmad92 **Github** sameerAhmad9291

SKILLS

BACKEND	Typescript, Javascript, C#, NodeJS, NestJS, Microservices, nosql, Serverless, JestJs, Sentry, sql
FRONTEND	ReactJS, Angular
DEVOPS	Kubernetes, Docker, GCP, AWS, Github

EXPERIENCE

Qured

Senior Software Engineer Oct 2021 - Present

Qured is the preventative healthcare platform that supports your employees through their unique health journeys.

- Led the integration of Cypress for comprehensive testing of critical customer workflows.
- Contributed to R&D efforts in the healthcare domain on Google Cloud Platform (GCP), specifically focusing on Mapping FHIR
 resources into qured product domain.
- Designed and implemented a system for handling inbound and outbound CSV files for the laboratory.
- Established Cloud Build triggers for continuous deployment pipeline of microservices.
- Played a key role in B2B customer onboarding by implementing a CSV import process.
- Developed and implemented Google Cloud Platform (GCP) SDK for Pub/Sub, task queue and logger, ensuring scalable and efficient backend infrastructure.
- Enhanced API request stack tracking through the integration of Sentry and improving error handling.
- Integrated API SDKs for third-party services including Klaviyo, QuickBlox, and Huboo.
- Collaborated closely with Product Owners to analyze task requirements, delivering user stories.
- Conducted thorough code reviews and actively participated in pair programming sessions.

AionDigital

Senior Backend Engineer Mar 2021 - Sep 2021

- Design and development of graphql mutation/queries.
- Integration KFH Bank APIs.
- Web application development experience using Angular.
- Write clean, modular web-based applications in an agile environment.
- Assist Developers with other tasks.

Netsol

Senior Full Stack Developer Oct 2019 - Feb 2021

Netsol - Otoz develop technology for companies to enter the mobility space and grow sustainable, profitable businesses.

- Third-party API integrations including Stripe, Plaid payment gateway and MiTek SDK for instant license verification.
- Identification and implementation of microservices for scalable web architecture.
- Azure Service Bus and rabbitmq queue for microservice communication.
- Worked the performance team to enhance API performance and increase Throughput.
- Worked closely with product owner's to take ownership of product's metrics.
- Troubleshooting, building, maintaining modern web applications.
- Collaboration with mobile and frontend team on backend APIs.
- Custom npm packages for core application functionality.
- Conducted code reviews and pair programming.

Vodworks

Senior Full Stack Developer Sep 2018 - Oct 2019

Vodworks provide software services around the globe.

- Automate of invoice process system. Monitoring inboxes for incoming bills & invoices and updating the relevant systems.
- Generating ESAL invoice files & mailing them to the client's email addresses.
- Conduct a performance comparison b/w Golang and NodeJS.
- Build accessible user interfaces in angular.
- Developing RESTful APIs and integration with SPA.
- Feature development and bug fixing.

Enlife AG

Software Engineer Apr 2015 - Nov 2018

Enlife AG is a smart energy technology company delivering cloud based energy engagement solutions to residential & enterprise customers.

- R&D on smart devices integration and installation.
- Developed reporting, analytical and charts dashboard.
- Debian OS and automation tools in OrangPi.
- Responsible for creating deployment releases.
- IoT devices integration and gather data.
- Real time experience for customer analytics.
- Extraction of multiple type meters reading.
- Responsive and reusable UI components.
- Alerts generation process.
- Experience in building Ionic app.

EDUCATION

COMSATS University Lahore

Feb 2011 - Feb 2015

Bachelor - Computer Science

LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

REFERENCES

He is a detail oriented and organized resource a manager would love working with. His development skills are commendable. He is a quick learner and detail oriented professional. His hardworking and striving skills to achieve for the best; distinguish from other. He is one of the rare resources, I have worked with, to whom you can rely on. I wish him good luck for future endeavors.

— Usman Parvez

Sameer Ahmad was one of the best resource in my team. He has excellent social and technical skills which make him stand out from the crowd. His ability to take on tasks beyond his knowledge was commendable as he never said no to an assigned task and was always willing to go above and beyond to research and resolve / complete them. I wouldn't think twice about taking him on my team whenever given a chance.

- Muhammad Imran